BRIAN CHAMBERS

347.720.3941 • brianchambers876@gmail.com

Exceptional problem-solving and technical troubleshooting skills honed by finding creative solutions independently and collaboratively. Excellent communication skills honed by over three years of assisting undergraduates and high school students in developing their coding prowess. Fast learner with the ability to adapt to changing environments.

EDUCATION

Hunter College, New York, NY

December 2020

Bachelor's in Computer Science

SKILLS

Teamwork, Communication, Lesson Planning, Technical Troubleshooting

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

AllStarCode, New York, NY

June 2021 - August 2021

Lead Instructor

- Lead the delivery of All Star Code's Technical Curriculum to two cohorts of 20 students.
- Evaluated and tracked quantitative and qualitative student progress by administering technical assessments and weekly student surveys.
- Managed an instructional team of one Teaching Assistant and one Teaching Fellow.

Comp Sci High, Bronx, NY

March 2021 - Present

AP Computer Science Teacher

- Create and deliver, virtually and in-person, a Technical Curriculum in Python to prepare students for the College Board's AP Computer Science Principles exam.
- Develop students' problem-solving abilities through technical labs and coding projects.
- Host in-person and remote office hours to support students, one-on-one or in groups, as needed to further clarify material.

Hunter College, New York, NY

August 2019 – December 2020

Teaching Assistant

- Provided in-class and remote teaching support to undergraduates for Object Oriented Programming and Data Structures in C++.
- Assisted upwards of 600 students with debugging and provide guidance to improve their programming technique and efficiency by emphasizing problem-solving and computational thinking through programming.
- Lead in-person and remote labs, guiding students one-on-one or in groups by breaking down the material and elaborating on new concepts.

Stony Brook University Audio Visual Services, Stony Brook, NY

October 2015 - May 2018

Senior Assistant

- Facilitated development and implementation of technical training programs for new team members and university instructors. Tracked development of team members over time to inform further development plans.
- Provided user support and troubleshooting for lecture hall presentation equipment including computers, projectors, printers, speakers, audio hubs, cameras, and classroom control systems for 150+ classes.
- Measured and analyzed usage of services and equipment to inform procurement for department.

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

Stony Brook University HeForShe, Stony Brook, NY

September 2017 - May 2018

Treasurer (Volunteer)

- Planned and facilitated weekly general body meetings for twenty members; collaborated with executive board to offer workshops, engaged in dialogue around current events and developed strategic fundraising plans.
- Monitored budget of \$5,000 for events promoting gender equality; recorded and reported club expenditure.